克莱蒂特先生
Mr. Cretites?
保罗・克莱蒂特
...Paul Cretites.
我是拉蒂默
My name is Latimer.
我是来接你的 克莱蒂特先生
I've come to meet you, Mr. Cretites.
这边请 克莱蒂特先生
Just come this way, Mr. Cretites.
我们已经为你备好了一辆马车
We have a carriage waiting.
希腊译员
我和福尔摩斯认识已久
During my long and intimate acquaintance
亲密无间
with Sherlock Holmes,
但从未听他提起过他的家人
I'd never heard him refer to his relations,
也很少听他讲起自己早年的生活
and hardly ever to his own early life.
他这样沉默寡言 我有时
Because of this reticence, I sometimes found myself
会认为他是个孤僻的怪人
regarding him as an isolated phenomenon
缺少同情心
as deficient in human sympathy
但又有着过人的智慧
as he was pre-eminent in intelligence.
我开始认为他是个孤儿
I'd come to believe that he was an orphan
没有亲人在世了
with no relatives living.
但是有一天 让我倍感惊奇的是
But one day, to my very great surprise,
他居然和我谈起了他的家庭
he began to talk to me about his family.
我独一无二的洞察力
My singular gift of observation introduction
可能是遗传自我奶奶
may have come from my grandmother,
她是法国艺术家巴内的妹妹
who was a sister of Bernais, the French artist.
血液中的这种艺术成分
The art in the blood
很容易具有最奇特的遗传形式
is liable to take the strangest forms.
比如说 我哥哥 迈克罗夫
For example, my brother, Mycroft.
你哥哥
Your brother?
我一直都不知道你有个哥哥
I didn't know you had a brother?
噢 没错
Oh, yes.
而且我可以向你保证
And I can assure you,
他身上具备了比我更惊人的
he possesses a far greater faculty
观察和推理能力
of observation and deduction than I do.
福尔摩斯 我知道你是个谦虚的人
Holmes, I know that you are a modest man
哈哈
Ha-ha.
我亲爱的华生
My dear Watson,
我可不能同意你
I cannot agree with those
把谦虚看成是一种美德
that rank modesty among the virtues.
对于逻辑学家来说
To the legation,
所有东西该什么样就什么样
everything should be seen exactly as it is.
一个人低估自己
And to underestimate one's self
同夸大自己的才能一样
is as much a departure from the truth
只会让他背离真相
as to exaggerate one's own ability.
我所说的关于我哥哥的一切
What I have just told you about my brother
都是准确真实的
is the exact and literal truth.
好吧 我当然相信你所说的
Well, naturally, I don't doubt your word.
但如果英格兰真的有另一个
But if there is another man in England
有着如此超凡能力的人
with such singular powers,
那为何警察 公众
how is it that neither the police nor the public
甚至包括我 都没听说过他呢?
have ever heard of him, let alone myself?
他在他自己的圈子里颇有名气
He's very well known in his own circles.
什么圈子?
Where then?
第欧根尼俱乐部
The Diagones Club.
那是伦敦最奇怪的俱乐部
It is the oddest club in London,
而我哥哥则是里面最怪的人之一
and my brother one of the oddest men.
你肯定很想见见他吧
I suppose you wish to meet him?
那是当然
Well, of course I do,
尽管我只是想证实有这样一个人的存在
even if it's just to prove that he exists.
那么下午你就可以得到答案了
Then you shall, this afternoon.
他遇到了一个很奇特的案件
He has come across the most singular problem,
而且觉得我会有兴趣
which he thinks might interest me.
但是为什么迈克罗夫
But why does Mycroft not use
不靠他自己超群的推理能力来破案呢?
his great powers for detective work?
如果侦探这门艺术只是
If the art of the detective began
靠坐在扶手椅上推理就行的话
and ended in reasoning from an arm chair,
我哥哥恐怕要成为历史上
my brother would be the greatest criminal agent
最伟大的侦探了
that ever lived.
我赖以为生的侦探业务
What is to me a means of livelihood
对他来说仅是兴趣而已
is to him the merest hobby of a dilettante.
他没有此方面的抱负 也没有这个精力
But he has no ambition and no energy.
他的职业是什么?
What is his profession, then?
他有着惊人的数字天赋
He has an extraordinary faculty for figures.
他帮政府部门
He audits the books
查账
for some of the government departments.
那么这个俱乐部的会员
But what are the qualifications
都是些什么样的人呢?
for the Diogenes Club?
有些为人低调 有些愤世嫉俗
Shyness and misanthropy...
我哥哥是创始人之一
my brother is one of the founding members.
那里接纳了镇上最孤僻
It contains the most unsociable
和最不爱交际的人 他们从不交谈
and clubful men in time who speak not a word
即使是他人的随意一瞥也会躲开
and shun even the merest glance.
好了 我们进去吧
Now, let us enter.
好 但是...
Yes, but...
什么都不要说了
Not a word.
福尔摩斯 你有没有...
Holmes, have you...
这里可以说话了
We can talk in here.
噢 谢天谢地
Well, thank goodness.
看那两个人 夏洛克
Look at those two men, Sherlock.
你有什么看法?
What do you make of them?
其中一个是弹子记分员
The brilliant marker of the other.
不错
Precisely.
那另一个呢?
What do you make of the other?
应该是一个老兵
An old soldier, I perceive.
而且最近心烦意乱
And very recently distraught?
他在印度服役
Served in India, I see.
是个军士
And a non-commissioned officer.
我猜 是皇家炮兵队的
Relativity, I fancy.
是个鳏夫
And a widower?
还带着一个孩子
With a child.
不止一个 我亲爱的弟弟 是几个孩子
Children, my dear boy, children.
哈哈
Ha-ha.
迈克罗夫・福尔摩斯
Mycroft Holmes.
很高兴见到你 华生医生
Glad to meet you, Dr. Watson.
自从你为夏洛克作传
I hear of Sherlock everywhere
我到哪都能听到他的事迹
since you became his...
噢 谢谢
Well, thank you.
如果谁想研究人类
For anyone who wishes to study mankind,
这就是最好的地方
this is the spot.
可你们刚才讨论的东西
But surely you were taking things
也太玄乎了
a little too far just now?
这其实很好推测出 华生
It is not hard to say, Watson,
他的举止
that a man of that bearing,
他威武的神情
and especially of authority
风吹日晒的皮肤 一望而知他是个军人
and some big skin as a soldier
而且不是一个普通的军人
is more than a private,
而且他刚从印度回来
and is not long for India.
他刚退伍不久还表现在
That is not long since left the service
他仍穿着炮兵靴子
shown by his still wearing his ammunition boots,
他们都这么叫的
as they're called.
他走起路来不像骑兵
He has not the cavalry stride,
但是他歪戴着帽子
but he wore his hat on one side
这一点可以从他一侧眉毛上边
as is shown by the lighter skin
较浅的皮肤看出来
on one side of his brow.
他的体重不符合工程兵的要求
His weight is against him being a sapper.
所以他应该在炮兵队
He is in the artillery.
他悲伤的神情
There goes his complete mourning shows
表示他失去了某个至亲之人
that he has lost someone very dear.
从他自己出来买东西这点看来
The fact that he's doing his own shopping
他失去了他的妻子
looks as though it was his wife.
你看 他在给孩子们买东西
He's been buying things for children, as you can see.
还有一个拨浪鼓
There is a wrap, which shows that one of them
说明有一个孩子很小
is very, very young.
而他的腋下夹了一本图画书
And the fact that he has a picture book under his arm
说明还有另外一个孩子
shows there is another child.
啊哈 梅拉斯先生来了
Aha, Mr. Merlas.
请进吧 先生
Come in, sir.
这些都是我的朋友
These are my friends.
这位是华生医生
This is Dr. Watson,
这是我的弟弟 夏洛克
and this is my younger brother, Sherlock.
你就是夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生?
You're Mr. Sherlock Holmes?
是我把梅拉斯先生叫来的
I've asked Mr. Merlas to step across.
他就住在我楼上
He lodges on the first floor above me,
我想你会对他的故事感兴趣的
and I thought you'd be interested in his story.
就是因为他 我才要你今天来的
He's the reason why I asked you to call today.
梅拉斯先生
Mr. Merlas,
他来找我...
he came to me, well...
我想还是让他自己
But I think I shall ask Mr. Merlas to tell
把他难忘的遭遇
his own very remarkable experiences
告诉你吧
in his own fashion.
谢谢你 福尔摩斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Holmes.
这些年来
For many years,
我在伦敦希腊翻译员中
I have been the chief
首屈一指
Greek interpreter in London.
警察恐怕是不会相信我所说的事的
I do not think that the police believe my story.
就连我自己都很难相信
On my word, I do not.
因为他们以前从未听过这样的事
Just because they have never heard of it before,
他们认为这样的事不可能发生
they think that such a thing cannot be.
但我知道 除非我弄清那个脸上
But I know that I shall never be easy in my mind
贴着橡皮膏的可怜人的遭遇
until I know what has become of my poor man
否则 我的心里是决不会轻松的
with a sticking plastered up on his face.
橡皮...
Sticky...
梅拉斯先生 你坐下说吧
Mr. Merlas, please sit down.
谢谢 福尔摩斯先生 我宁愿站着
Thank you, Mr. Holmes, I prefer to stand.
华生
Watson.
我都听着呢
I am all attention.
这一切都发生在两天前
All this happened only two days ago,
就是周一晚上
on Monday night.
正如之前说的 我是个希腊人
I am Greek by instruction.
以翻译为生
And earn my living as an interpreter.
在一些不寻常的时间
It often happens that I'm sent for at strange hours
常常会有一些有困难的外国人
by foreigners who would get into difficulties
或是晚到的游客
or by travelers who would arrive late
来找我帮他们翻译
and wish my services.
梅拉斯先生
Mr. Merlas?
什么事?
Yes?
我很抱歉现在提出这个请求
I apologize for this intrusion,
但我现在急需
but I need the services
一个翻译
of an interpreter immediately.
我的名字叫拉蒂默
My name is Latimer.
现在就要去?
Immediately?
确实很紧急才来找你的
I wouldn't insist unless it were urgent,
我有个希腊朋友因公事
but a Greek friend of mine has just arrived
刚来到这儿
in this country on business matter.
不幸的是
Unfortunately, he speaks nothing
他只会讲希腊语
but his own tongue.
我也只会讲英语
I likewise so.
梅拉斯先生 拜托你了
Mr. Merlas, please.
马车已经在外面等着了
My carriage is waiting outside.
很远吗?
How far away?
就在肯辛顿
Only to Kensington.
很抱歉挡住你的视线了
I'm sorry to have to cut off your view, Mr. Merlas,
我不能让你看到
but the fact is, I have no intention that you
我们要去的地方
should see the place to which we are driving.
如果你再找到原路回来
It might possibly be inconvenient to me
我会有小麻烦的
if you were able to find your way back again.
这实在是一种越规的行为 拉蒂默先生
This is very extraordinary conduct, Mr. Latimer.
要知道 你的行为
You must be aware that what you're doing
可是违法的
is quite illegal.
毫无疑问 这有点失礼
It is somewhat of a liberty, no doubt,
但我们会给你补偿的
but we'll make it up to you.
马车行使了将近两个小时
For nearly two hours, we drove,
但我丝毫不知道我在何处
without my having the least idea as to where I was.
你注意到
Did you not notice any change
轮子下的声音有什么变化吗?
of sound under the wheels?
我仔细听了 福尔摩斯先生
I listened, Mr. Holmes.
有时候好像走在石板路上
Sometimes we seemed to be on a paved causeway,
有时候又好像是柏油路
sometimes on asphalt,
但都不足以让我判断出到底身在何处
but there was nothing to tell me where I was.
没有其他的声音了吗
And no other sounds...
比如说轮船的汽笛声 或是教堂的钟声?
a ship's siren or church bell?
很抱歉 都没有
I'm sorry, nothing like that.
大约在什么时间
At what time
你们到了目的地?
did you finally reach your destination?
8:50
Ten minutes to 9:00, exactly.
这位就是梅拉斯先生吗 哈罗德?
Is this Mr. Merlas, Harold.
是的
Yes.
做得好 哈哈哈
Well done, Ha Ha Ha,
做得好
well done.
我们没有恶意 梅拉斯先生
No ill will, Mr. Merlas, I trust,
可没有你 我们办不成事
but we could not get on without you.
如果你对我们诚实 你是不会后悔的
If you deal fair with us, you'll not regret it,
但如果你耍花招 那就自求多福吧
but if you try any tricks, God help you.
你们想要我做什么?
What do you want of me?
只是向拜访我们的希腊绅士
Only to ask a few questions
问几个问题
of a Greek gentleman who's visiting us,
并告诉我们他的答复
and to let us have the answers.
但是你不得多嘴
But, you say no more than you are told,
要不然 小心你的小命
or it were better you had never been born.
梅拉斯先生 请继续
Mr. Merlas, pray continue.
好的 然后这个人 恶毒的人
Well then, this man, this evil man,
把我带到了
showed me to a room which appeared to be
一间装修得很奇怪的房间
very curiously furnished.
房间的唯一光线来自一盏
But again, the only light was afforded by a single lamp,
拧得很小的灯
half turned down.
拿石板给他 哈罗德
The slate, Harold.
给他的手松绑
Are his hands loose?
拿着这个
Take this.
你可以问问题了 梅拉斯先生
You will ask the questions, Mr. Merlas,
他会把答案写下来的
and he will write the answers.
先问他
Ask him, first of all,
他是否准备好在文件上签字
whether he's prepared to sign the papers?
绝不签
"Never. "
没有商量的余地?
On no conditions?
他说 除非我亲眼看到
He writes, "only if I see her married
她在我认识的希腊牧师作证下结婚
in my presence by a Greek priest, whom I know. "
哈哈
Ha Ha.
那你知道等着你的会是什么吗?
You know what awaits you, then?
他说 他不在乎自己会怎样
He says, "I care nothing for myself. "
就这样
And so it went on, again and again
我不得不再三问他是否
I had to ask him whether he would give in
愿意签那份文件
and sign the document.
但得到的都是同样的答案
Again and again, I had the same indignant reply.
很快 我就产生了一个想法
But soon, a thought came to me.
我在每次发问时加上自己要问的话
I took to adding on little sentences of my own
起初只是些无关紧要的话
to each question, innocent ones at first,
来试探我身边这些人
to test whether either of our companions
是否能听懂希腊语
knew anything of the matter.
然后我发现 他们毫无反应
And then, as I found that they showed no sign,
我便大胆探问起来
I played a more dangerous game.
倔强对你没好处
This obstinacy is doing you no good.
他说 我不在乎
He says, "I care not. "
实际上 他还告诉我
In fact, he had also told me
他在伦敦人生地疏
he was a stranger in London.
他说他来这已经三个星期了
He then told me he had been here three weeks,
而且还不给饭吃
and was being forcibly starved.
没饭吃?
Starved?
你问出他名字了吗?
Did you manage to find out his name?
克莱蒂特
Cretites.
从雅典来的
He was from Athens.
但是很不幸 我只问到这么多
But that was all I could discover, unfortunately.
要是再多给五分钟
Another five minutes,
我就可以打探出
and I should have wormed out
这整件事的来龙去脉
the whole story under their very noses.
再问他一遍 梅拉斯先生
Ask him again, Mr. Merlas.
就在这时 门开了
But at that instant, the door opened,
一个女人走了进来
and a woman stepped into the room.
他说 绝不
He says, "never. "
再问他!
Well, ask him again!
哈罗德 我再也不能多呆了
Harold, I could not stay away any longer.
索菲亚 索菲亚 索菲亚
Sophia, Sophia, Sophia!
好了 梅拉斯先生
That will do, Mr. Merlas.
你看
As you perceive,
我们没有拿你当外人
we have taken you into our confidence
才请你参与了我们的私事
over some very private business.
这里是五磅金币
Here are five sovereigns, which will, I hope,
我想作为酬劳足够了
be a sufficient fee.
但请记住 如果你对任何人透露今晚的事
But remember, if you speak to anyone about this,
只要对一个活人讲
one human soul, mind, well,
你的小命可就不保了
may God have mercy on your soul.
和去时一样 我上了一辆封闭的马车
As before, I was taken in a closed carriage
行使了大约两小时
for almost two hours.
我被他们丢下车 我才发现
There I was abandoned, as I was later to discover,
那是旺兹沃思荒地附近
near Wentsworth Common.
除了刚才对你讲的事情之外
I did not know where I had been,
我既不知所到何地
nor whom I had spoken with nor anything,
也不知和我谈话的是何人
saving what I have told you.
但我知道有人在进行肮脏的勾当
But I know there is foul play going on,
我想帮助那个可怜的人
and I want to help that unhappy man...
苍天作证 我会的
before God, I do.
迈克罗夫
Mycroft.
迈克罗夫!
Mycroft!
啊?
Huh?
采取什么措施了吗?
What steps have you taken so far?
这是登在日报上的
Well, this was in all the daily papers:
"如果有任何人能提供关于
"Anyone having information as to the whereabouts
"某不通英语的希腊绅士
of a Greek gentleman
保罗・克莱蒂特的信息
named Paul Cretites,
"当予重酬
who cannot speak English, will be rewarded.
"另外 如果您能提供关于
As ever a reward will be paid to anyone
"一位名叫索菲亚的希腊女士的信息
having information about a Greek lady,
"也将获得报酬"
whose first name is Sophia, "
但是还没有任何回复
but no answer as yet.
希腊公使馆那边有消息么?
What about the Greek Legation?
我问过了
I have tried.
他们对此一无所知
They know nothing.
那就快发电报给雅典警察局!
The head of the Athens police, then!
夏洛克是我们家精力最旺盛的一个
Sherlock has all the energy in the family.
你要用尽办法把案子查清
When you take up a case, by all means,
如果有好消息就告诉我!
let me know if you do any good!
一定
Certainly.
梅拉斯先生
Mr. Merlas, sir.
如果我是你
I should be extremely careful,
我一定会加倍小心
if I were you, but of course,
因为他们一看到这些广告
through these advertisements,
就会知道是你出卖了他们
they'll know that you've betrayed them.
噢
Whoops.
走路当心点
On your way.
在我看来 那个希腊姑娘很明显是
It seems to me obvious that this Greek girl has been
被那个叫哈罗德・拉蒂默的年轻英国人
carried off by the young Englishman,
给拐骗走的
Harold Latimer.
从哪拐骗来的?
Carried off from where?
可能是雅典
Athens, perhaps?
不不不 这个哈罗德・拉蒂默
No, no, no... this Harold Latimer
不会讲希腊语
cannot speak a word in Greek.
那个女孩英语讲得很流利
The girl speaks English fairly well,
这么说来 她应该在英格兰待过一段时间
inference that she has been in England some little time,
而他没去过希腊
and he has not been in Greece.
谢谢你 杰克森小姐
Thank you Miss Jackson.
好吧 那让我们假设那个女孩
Then, let's presume that the girl
来英格兰游玩 而那个哈罗德
was visiting in England and that this Harold
劝她和他私奔
persuaded her to fly with him.
这个可能性更大点
That is more probable.
然后她的哥哥 应该是她的亲戚
Then the brother, that must be the relationship,
从希腊前来干涉
comes over from Greece in order to intervene,
他们看到了他
they see him,
用武力强迫他签下一些文件
use violence to force him to sign some documents,
把女孩的财产转移到他们的名下
making over the girl's fortune to them.
他可能是财产的受托人
He's probably the trustee.
然后 就像我们听到的 他拒绝签字
This, as we have heard, he refuses to do.
至今仍不妥协
So far.
那些人不会善罢甘休
But these men will not stop now.
不论发生什么 我们都必须找到他们
Whatever happens, Watson, we must find them.
怎么找?
How can we?
如果我们的推测没错
Well, if our conjecture is correct,
这姑娘的名字应该是索菲亚・克莱蒂特
and the girl's name is... or was... Sophia Cretites,
要找到她应该不难
we should have no difficulty in tracing her.
那是我们的主要希望
That must be our main hope.
因为他哥哥在城里没人认识他
The brother, of course, is a complete stranger.
进来 夏洛克
Come in, Sherlock.
进来 先生
Come in, sir.
你没想到我有如此精力 是不是 夏洛克?
You don't expect such energy from me, do you, Sherlock
嗯?
...hmm?
你是怎么来的?
Now, How did you get here?
你们在电报局的时候我赶过了你们
I passed you while you were in the telegraph office.
我登的广告有回复了
I had an answer to my advertisement.
就在你们离开不久
It came within a few minutes of your leaving.
有什么消息?
And what effect?
是用宽尖钢笔写在淡黄色纸上的
It is written with a Jay pen on royal cream paper
写信人是个身体孱弱的中年男人
by a middle-aged man with a weak constitution.
"阁下 鉴于您今天登报所提及的女士
"Sir, in answer to your advertisement of today's date,
"我很荣幸告知您
I beg to inform you that I know the young lady
"我对她非常了解
in question very well.
"欲知详情 请到鄙处一坐
If you should care to call upon me,
"当能告知
I could give you some particulars
"她过去痛苦的经历
as to her painful history.
"她现正在贝克纳姆之默特尔兹
She's at present at Memerkle's Beckinum.
"此致敬礼 杰・达文波特"
Yours faithfully, Jay Davenport. "
是从下布里克斯顿寄来的
He writes from Lower Brigestone.
我们现在何不到那
Do you not think we should drive there now
去把详情了解一番?
and learn these particulars?
我亲爱的迈克罗夫
My dear Mycroft.
她哥哥的生命
Her brother's life is more important
比妹妹的故事更加重要
than the sister's story.
但是我们得先去苏格兰场
But we should call at Scotland Yard
找格雷森警长
for Inspector Gregson
然后直接去贝克纳姆
and then go straight out to Beckinum,
要知道 那人的性命正危在旦夕
where we know that a man is being done to death,
我们要争分夺秒
Every hour maybe vital.
要不要顺便去接梅拉斯先生?
Better pick up Mr. Merlas on the way?
接他干吗?
Why?
因为我们需要一个希腊翻译啊
Because we may need a Greek interpreter.
说得好 华生
Excellent, Watson.
据我们所了解到的线索 我得说
I should say from what we have heard,
我们遇到的
that we are dealing with
是个很危险的对手
a particularly dangerous guy.
梅拉斯先生?
Mr. Merlas?
什么事?
Yes.
楼下有位先生要见你
There's a gentleman downstairs to see you, sir.
哪位先生?
What gentleman?
他说是今天和你
Well, he said he met you today
在第欧根尼俱乐部见面的先生
at the Diogenes Club.
福尔摩斯先生 谢谢
Mr. Holmes! Thank you!
晚上好啊 梅拉斯先生
Good evening, Mr. Merlas.
晚上好 斯特德太太
Good evening, Mrs. Sterd,
麻烦你告知梅拉斯先生 我们有要事找他
Would you tell Mr. Merlas I need to see him urgently.
噢 梅拉斯先生现在不在这 先生
Well, Mr. Merlas is not here, sir.
刚刚有位绅士找他一起离开了
A gentleman just called for him, and he left.
你知道他们去哪了吗?
Can you tell me where?
这我可不知道 先生
Oh, I don't know, sir.
我只知道
All I know is,
他和那位绅士上了辆马车
he drove off with a gentleman in a carriage.
那位绅士有说他的名字吗?
Did the gentleman give a name?
没有 先生
No, sir.
他是不是一个年轻 英俊的黑大个?
He wasn't a tall, handsome, dark, young man?
噢 不是的 先生
Oh, no, sir.
他个子不高 戴着眼睛
He was a little gentleman, with glasses,
脸很瘦 但是很有礼貌
thin in the face, but very pleasant in his ways.
他说话的时候一直都在笑呢
He was laughing all the time he was talking.
谢谢您
Thank you.
去苏格兰场 快!
Scotland Yard, and hurry!
没有许可证可行不通
It cannot be done without a warrant!
先别管许可证了 长官
We are not disputing that, Inspector.
就算他们是罪犯
Even if they are criminals,
那也是私人住宅 法律规定...
it is a private house and the law demands...
法律规定我们要快点了
The law demands that we act quickly.
你就不能找个地方法官
Can you not find a Magistrate
给我们签张许可证吗?
to sign this warrant for us?
就现在?
A this hour?
就现在
At this very minute
要不然绑架案就要变成谋杀案了
our kidnapping could become murder.
那我试试吧
I can but try.
请快点
Please do.
告诉他 我已经失去理智了
Tell him, I have ceased being reasonable.
如果他还不签字
If he does not sign the papers now,
我就杀了他
I will kill him.
告诉他 我已经没有耐性了
Tell him I have no more patience.
不
No.
求求你了 警长
Please, Inspector...
非得要许可证吗?
will you not come without a warrant?
很抱歉 先生
I am sorry, gentlemen...
我们已经浪费了快一个小时了
We have wasted nearly an hour.
法律可催不得 福尔摩斯先生
The law cannot be hurried, Mr. Holmes.
梅拉斯先生的命
The life of Mr. Merlas
现在就掌握在你手中了 警长
is in your hands, Inspector.
告诉他 呃 告诉他如果我杀了他
Tell him... hmm... tell him if I kill him...
他妹妹对我也没任何用处了
...I have no use anymore...
所以她也得死
...for his sister, and she will die, also.
但是你不能...      告诉他!
But you wouldn't...        TELL HIM!
好了 先生们 签好了
Here it is, gentlemen... it's signed.
现在快找个人把我们载到
Now get someone to drive us
伦敦桥站去吧
to London Bridge Station.
但愿还不算太晚
I pray we're not too late!
一辆满载着行李四轮马车
A carriage heavily loaded with luggage
半小时前刚开走
has passed that within the last half-hour.
在这里等我们
Wait for us here.
贼窝已经空了
The nest is empty and the birds are flown.
是硫磺!
It's sulfur!
迈克罗夫 拿着灯!
Mycroft, get the lamp!
过来 帮我把他们搬出来
Come, help me with the bodies!
很好!
Right!
快!
Quick!
这个可怜人肯定就是保罗・克莱蒂特
The poor wretch must be Paul Cretites.
恐怕不再是了 他已经死了
No more, I'm afraid. His life is over.
我们应该早点来的 警长
We should have been here sooner, Inspector!
他已经死了大约4个小时了
He must have been dead about four hours.
那些气体是硫磺
The gas made of sulfur,
我没说错吧 华生医生?
am I not right, Dr. Watson?
他是被打死的
Beaten to death.
但是梅拉斯先生还活着
But Mr. Merlas still lives.
快 赶快把他搬出去
Quick! Let's get him out of here as fast as possible!
警长 快去拿白兰地!
Inspector, brandy!
放松 梅拉斯先生 你现在安全了
Relax, Mr. Merlas, you're in safe hands.
把他身上的绳索解开
Get the ropes off him.
我粗略看了一下那位女士的房间
From a brief look at her room,
她已经匆匆忙忙地离开了
the lady left in haste,
但没有打斗痕迹
but without a struggle.
那个叫拉蒂默的男人对她肯定还有控制力
That man Latimer must still have some power over her.
我想知道
One wonders,
她为了哈罗德・拉蒂默
with how much remorse she abandoned her brother
而抛弃她哥哥会不会懊悔
for Harold Latimer?
你还是对妇女抱有偏见?
You still retain your low opinion of women?
在此事上 我可能无法公平看待
In this instance, I cannot maybe justify.
福尔摩斯 他们好像查询过列车时刻表
Holmes, they appear to have consulted a Bradshaw.
看这里
Look at this page.
是联运火车
The boat train.
凶手走不远的
The murderers won't get far.
我可以在英格兰每个港口都派人守着
Have man at every port in England, if need be.
这辆车在伦敦和多佛之间会停一次
The boat train makes one stop between London and Dover.
停在霍恩山 23分钟
At Hurn Hill in 23 minutes, precisely.
很好 警长 你就陪着这位第一目击者
Exactly. Stay with your chief witness, Inspector.
你可能需要给他录份笔录
You may need a statement from him.
而且他需要你的帮助
And he will need your help.
让他喝点白兰地和阿摩尼亚
A little brandy, and ammonia at frequent intervals.
迈克罗夫! 我可没法跑那么快
Mycroft, I'm not built for running so hard!
请出示你的车票!
Tickets, please!
你就不能把票给准备好吗?
Will you kindly have your tickets ready, please?
我叫夏洛克・福尔摩斯
My name is Sherlock Holmes.
夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生?
Mr. Sherlock Holmes?
我看过你的破案故事
Well, I've read about your cases, sir.
根据验票情况
Are we the last passengers
我们是最后上车的乘客了吧?
from whom you have collected tickets?
没错 先生 我一直在火车上工作 从另一头开始
Indeed, sir. I always work at the engine, start there,
一路验票到这
and work my way back to the garden.
那你就可以帮我了
Then you can help me.
有三个乘客 两男一女
There are three passengers, two men and a woman,
一起坐车
traveling together.
他们也许表现得不像同伴
They may not appear to be companions,
但一定呆在同一间车厢
but they will be in a compartment alone.
年纪大点的带着副厚厚的眼镜
The elder man wears thick-lensed glasses,
年轻的那个长的很英俊
and the younger one is quite handsome.
他们带了很多行李
They will have a great deal of luggage
上面有前往欧洲的标记
marked for the Continent.
你有见过他们吗?
Have you seen such a party?
有见过 我可以帮你 福尔摩斯先生
Yes, indeed, I can help you, Mr. Holmes.
我就知道
I never doubted it.
火车上有两组人
There are two parties
符合你的描述 福尔摩斯先生
who fit that description, Mr. Holmes.
两组?
Two?
请出示你的车票
Ticket, please.
在B4号房间
In Compartment B4...
B4      还有D8
B4.        ...and D8.
谢谢你 乘务员
Thank you, Inspector.
你怎样知道哪两个是凶手?
How do you know which two are the murderers?
再简单不过了 不 别吵醒他
It couldn't be simpler. No, don't wake him.
我们两个去就行了
There's danger enough for the two of us.
有一个是来自代佛德的左撇子出版商
A left-handed printer from Detford.
他的哥哥喝多了
His older brother drinks too much
而且还有肝病
and is pained by his liver.
不是我们要找的
Can't harm mine then.
是啊
Whatever.
那这个女孩呢
And the girl?
她不认识这两个男的
She knows neither of them,
她是个布拉福德的机械师
she's a machinist from Bradford
是去度假的
who's going on a Holiday
顺便寻找爱情
to find romance.
这些都说明
Which means, undoubtedly,
凶手不在B4
the murderers aren't in Compartment B4.
谢谢你 克莱蒂特小姐
Thank you, Miss Cretites.
坐着不要动 拉蒂默先生 进来吧 华生
Do sit still, Mr. Latimer. Do come in, Watson.
你究竟是谁?
Who the hell are you?
还有一个人不在这里
The third member of the party is absent,
但我肯定他会回来的
but I'm sure he will return.
克莱蒂特小姐 我能问你个问题吗?
Miss Cretites, may I ask
是这个男人绑架你还是你自愿跟他走的
if you are this man's prisoner or companion?
什么都不要说
Don't say anything.
他们没有权利问你任何问题
They have no right to ask you anything at all.
如果他们是警察的话 早就自报家门了
If they were the police, they would have said so.
为什么是警察呢 拉蒂默先生?
Why the police, Mr. Latimer?
难道你知道他们会来?
Were you expecting to meet them?
听着 我不知道你到底是谁
Look, I don't know who you are,
我也不知道你是怎么知道我的名字的
nor do I know how you know my name,
但我正和我的未婚妻
but I'm traveling with my fiancee
前往欧洲 准备在那结婚
to the Continent to get married.
所以 麻烦你们离开好吗?
So, would you please leave us alone?
要不然 我就要叫警卫了
Otherwise, I shall be obliged to call a guard.
那你就叫吧
Please do.
我肯定华生乐意代为效劳
I'm sure Dr. Watson would do it for you.
啊 想必你是知道我是谁了
Ah, I see you know who I am?
那么 我能否
Then may I be permitted to ask
再问你未婚妻一次呢?
your fiancee the question again?
他说得没错
It's true what he said.
我们是要去结婚的
We are going to be married?
去哪?
Where?
雅典
In Athens.
恐怕去不了了
I fear not.
谁敢阻挡我们?
And who is going to stop us?
如果警察不阻止 我也会
If not the police, then I will.
克莱蒂特小姐 你真的是
Miss Cretites, do you seriously want me to believe
自愿离开英格兰的吗?
that you are leaving England willingly?
是的
Yes.
为了嫁给这个谋杀了你哥哥的男人?
To marry the man who has just murdered your brother?
那不是真的
That's not true.
不 谋杀?
No! Murdered?
这不是真的 对吗?
It isn't true, is it?
他身体康复后会尽快来希腊和我们会合
He's going to meet us in Greece as soon as he's well.
你是这样对我说的
That's what you said to me.
他会的 索菲亚 他会的
And he will Sophia, he will.
你哥哥死了 克莱蒂特小姐
Your brother is dead, Miss Cretites.
别听他胡说
Don't listen to him.
我在贝克纳姆的房子里发现了他的尸体
I found his body myself in the house in Beckinum.
他被杀死了
He had been murdered.
被折磨致死的
tortured to death.
不 这不是真的
No, it can't be.
哈罗德 告诉我 到底怎么回事?
Harold, tell me what's happened!
至于你 拉蒂默先生
As for you, Mr. Latimer,
梅拉斯先生还活着
Mr. Merlas is alive
作为证人他将亲眼看着你被绞死
as a witness to see you hanged.
救我 索菲亚 救我!
Help me, Sophia, help me!
救我! 救我!
Help me! Help me!
...那很不错 非常好
...went very well, very well indeed.
我有朋友死了
I have friends dead.
我想不用我多说了
Yes, but I need not elaborate,
在我看来 你是个阅历丰富的人 对吗?
as I see you are a man of the world, sir?
相反
On the contrary...
我从未离开过英格兰
I've never left England in my life.
真的吗?
Haven't you?
没有
No.
那么先生 如果你一定要选一个国家
Then sir, if you must choose one country,
那就选希腊
it must be Greece...
众神之岛 还有橄榄枝和阴谋
the land of Gods, olives and intrigue.
那是我的目的地 希腊
It is my destination, Greece.
那你会说希腊语吗 先生?
Do you speak Greek, sir?
不会 但我们能找个好翻译啊
No, but one can always find a good interpreter.
谢谢
Thank you.
真是美味佳肴
An excellent meal.
那么 再见了 先生
well, good bye, sir.
能够遇见你是我的荣幸
It was a pleasure meeting you.
再见
Well, good bye.
和你聊得很愉快
It was an interesting conversation.
真是抱歉
I do apologize.
有时候我会忘了自己有多重
Sometimes, I forget my size.
再见了
Goodbye again.
保罗的事是真的吗?
Is it true about Paul?
是的 我很抱歉
I'm afraid so.
我恨哈罗德・拉蒂默
I hated Harold Latimer.
我恨他 同时我也爱他
I hated him, and I loved him.
我愿意做他要我做的任何事
I would have done anything he said.
我愿意和他去任何地方
I would have gone anywhere with him.
即使他杀了你哥哥?
Even though he murdered your brother?
是的
Yes, even then.
凯纳先生
Mr. Cana,
我们正等着你呢
we were expecting you.
这是你的左轮手枪吧 先生?
I believe this is your revolver, sir?
我亲爱的哥哥...
Well, brother of mine...
我们似乎走上了犯罪的道路了
we seem to be heading down the path of crime.
我唯一想走的
The only path I intend to take
是去往第欧根尼俱乐部大门的路
is the door to the Diogenes Club,
你们可别跟来
which I will close behind me.
她会怎样?
What will become of her?
问几个问题就没事了
After questioning, nothing.
她虽冷血 无情
There's not a crime to her cold heart,
但还构不上犯罪
and not a single shred of compassion.
-==www.RagBear.com==-